[Music]
welcome back friends of physiology
science nutrition and strength training
and all the other crap I post up in
these YouTube videos today we're talking
about how you store and transform your
different macronutrients this is really
honestly a condensed primer if you will
for a lot of other videos that have
where we explain to you
performance biochemistry physiology and
nutrition okay but this is important
starter kit if you will or a reminder if
you want to do it that way now I'm
giving you the first one which is
carbohydrate and so most of you
recognize that the place that we or the
way that we transport if you will
carbohydrates is in the form of blood
glucose or blood sugar okay so if you
see if you get a blood draw and you want
to measure how many carbohydrates you're
transporting around your body you're
gonna measure glucose and the reason we
do that is because we want to get
glucose from one body part to another
part apart so we can use it we got to
transport it somehow and that's gonna be
in the form of our blood so to back up a
little bit there where do we actually
store where do we get it from well it
could be from the food you just ate
right there but realistically most of
its gonna be coming from your liver and
muscle in the form of glycogen okay now
that's a polysaccharide you can check
out the other videos for that all right
so we store our carbohydrates in the
form of not fat that's right Francis we
don't store carbides fat we store
Carbide it's carbohydrates in the form
of glycogen it's kind of like a starch
in a human and we put that in our liver
in our muscle with the vast majority of
that being in your muscle that's because
when we go to exercise one of the
primary fuel sources for exercise is
carbohydrate so if I want to use my
biceps which thank you very much they
have been getting bigger lately thank
you quarantine I'm gonna use the
carbohydrate the glucose that is in that
bicep that exercising muscle itself if I
need to get more of it because I starts
running you know I gotta get it from the
liver or another muscle I'm gonna break
it down release it as glucose through
the blood and transport it to wherever I
need it
our next category over here being fat
and to back up a little bit yes if you
do over consume carbohydrate a small
percentage of it can be stored as fat
when we're talking
like 1 to 5% it's very very minimal
depending on what's going on so we store
our fat as adipose tissue typically or a
couple other spots but we know that and
it's in the form of a triglyceride TG
okay you know if we go to use that fat
for fuel which we can we would break it
down just like we break down glycogen in
the blood and we move that as a free
fatty acid you take three fatty acids
together combine it with the glycerol
backbone you have yourself a
triglyceride and so that system works
very concisely just like the
carbohydrate thing does stored form of
glycogen transport cut it into six
carbon molecule call it glucose here cut
it in two or three fatty acid chains
move them around if we don't use that
that gets then restored back up there at
set just like you would do that here
okay now the last one is protein and
most of you know the building blocks of
proteins are amino acids right and so if
you are to transport a protein
throughout your body again you not have
a big chunk of protein that much
floating through your blood it's mostly
gonna be the form of the individual
amino acids that you get it if you go to
store that then that's just going to
simply be stored as a as a protein right
and then you can of course break the
protein back down transport it as amino
acids now we don't do a very good job as
humans as storing our amino acids okay
we can store a little bit in muscle but
for the most part it's transient you
leak it out and that's one of the other
reasons why unlike fat or carbohydrate
if you want to say maximize muscle
growth you probably need to get the
probe protein in pretty frequently
because you don't do a great job of
storyand all right these can be stored
for a long period of time okay hopefully
that helped hopefully you're enjoying
all these five minute physicists be sure
to check out 2005 55 minute versions at
this point I got a probably several
hundred hours of videos up
you
[Music]